admiral.com 2005-11-24

# Admiral car insurance

|  |  | 

| 

|  Your Privacy and Security |   
---|---  
  
### 1.   INTRODUCTION  
  
  | 

We are committed to respecting your privacy and to complying with applicable data protection and privacy laws. So, you can be assured that any information you provide to us will be used strictly in accordance with the terms laid out in this Privacy Statement.

We have provided this Privacy Statement to help you understand how we collect, use and protect your information when you call us or visit our web sites and when you generally use our products and services. We wish to help you make informed decisions so, please take a few moments to read the sections below and learn how we may use your personal information. You should also show this notice to anyone else who may be insured to drive the car covered under your policy.  
  
---|---  

### 2\.    HOW YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE USED

  | 

Your information will be used for a number of purposes which include: automatically processing your quotations; managing and administering your policy including claims handling; delivering any services, products or information requested by you; responding to complaints or policy enquiries; administering debt recoveries; verifying your identity when required (we take our data security very seriously and we may need to ask you for other 'identifiable' information to protect your data from unauthorised access); undertaking market and product analysis based on your use of our services and products; keeping you informed about products, services, promotions, special offers and new developments; fraud prevention and detection purposes; credit scoring or other automated decision making systems to process and record personal information.

Admiral Insurance Services Ltd may use your information to keep you informed by post, telephone or email of products and services including but not limited to car insurance, other automotive or financial products, or other carefully selected offers which it feels may interest you. If you do not wish your data to be used in this way, please write to the Marketing Department, Admiral Insurance Services Ltd, Capital Tower, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff, CF10 3AZ, who will ensure that your data is not used for such purposes.

In order to offer you the security of continuous cover on your policy, Admiral Insurance Services Limited will arrange for your policy to be automatically renewed when your cover expires.

You should be aware that Admiral Insurance Services Limited is only able to guarantee automatic renewal where:  
  
---|---  
  
  | 

(a)

| 

you have made us aware of any changes to your policy details (it is your responsibility to notify us of any changes);  
  
---|---|---  
|  |   
  | 

(b)

| 

the credit / debit card details submitted have not changed;  
  
|  |   
  | 

(c)

| 

the credit / debit card holder has explicitly consented to renewal premiums being charged to his or her card upon automatic renewal.  

  | 

Unless we hear from you to the contrary Admiral Insurance Services Limited is entitled to assume at the time of renewal that your details have not changed and you have the consent of the card holder as detailed.

Should you wish to make changes to your current policy during the term of that policy then, unless you inform us otherwise, Admiral Insurance Services Limited will charge the payment details held on record for any additional amount due.

You may inform us of changes in your circumstances or choose to opt out of automatic renewal at any time in writing or by contacting our Customer Service department.

We may also contact you with a reminder that your insurance is due for renewal. We may disclose information about you and your policy:  
  
---|---  
  
  | 

(i)

| 

to companies within the Admiral Group (including persons working for us) for the purposes and subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy Statement; and  
  
---|---|---  
|  |   
  | 

(ii)

| 

in the event that we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, in which case you agree that any personal information we hold about you may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party for the purposes and subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy Statement.  

  | 

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy Statement, "Admiral Group" means Admiral Group plc and any company or other entity in which Admiral Group plc owns (directly or indirectly) more than 15% of the issued share capital. Companies in the Admiral Group shall include, without limitation, Admiral Insurance Services Limited, Admiral Syndicate Management Limited, Admiral Syndicate Limited, Admiral Insurance Company Limited, Admiral Insurance (Gibraltar) Limited, Inspop.com Limited, Able Insurance Services Limited and any other company that is incorporated within the Admiral Group at any time in the future.  
  
---|---  
  
  | 

(iii)

| 

for your benefit and in order to ensure an efficient administrative process. We may discuss with and take instruction for change to your motor policy from yourself, spouse or partner, parents, and drivers already named on the motor policy. If you do not want us to do this then please write to the Underwriting department, Floor 23, Capital Tower, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AZ.  
  
---|---|---  
|  |   
  | 

(iv)

| 

where it is necessary to deliver the products and services ordered or used by you. For example, we may disclose your data to a credit card company to validate your credit card details and obtain payment when you buy our products or services. It may also be necessary for us to pass your data to the organisation from whom you have ordered any products or services other than your Admiral insurance product, such as a travel insurance or home insurance provider, a Personal Accident Cover provider, a Car Hire cover provider, etc. At all times, Admiral Insurance Services Limited will remain the Data Controller unless we inform you otherwise.  

  | 

We may also be obliged to disclose your personal information to meet any legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law.

You acknowledge that by providing data to us, you consent to the processing of your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy Statement.  
  
---|---  

### 3\.    COLLECTING INFORMATION

| 

**i)**

| 

**Personal**

We endeavour to collect and use your personal information only with your knowledge and consent and typically when you ask for a quote and purchase our products and services, make customer enquiries, register for information or other services, request product information, or when you respond to communications from us (such as questionnaires or surveys). When providing information relating to other persons who may be insured you confirm that you have the consent of these individuals to supply their personal details.

The type of personal information we may collect could include, for example, your name and postal address, date of birth, gender, telephone and mobile phone numbers, email address, and credit/debit card information; lifestyle and other information collected on registration or through surveys. If you choose to provide us with personal information, it will be used in support of the intended purposes stated at the time at which it was collected, and subject to any preferences indicated by you.  

Information defined as 'sensitive data' within the Data Protection Act 1998 includes for example, medical history, claims history, criminal convictions, etc. We may collect such information at various stages of our relationship with you and by accepting your policy with us you agree to us collecting such information. We are unable to offer you any insurance product unless you provide explicit consent for the collection and use of such sensitive data as defined in the Act. All personal information will be held in strictest confidence and used only for the purposes for which we collect it.  

If you would like us to remove any personal information from our records, then please write to us at our Customer Services Department, Capital Tower, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AZ. Please be ready to quote your full name, address and if applicable your policy number when contacting us. We will make all reasonable efforts to delete your information from our files if it is deemed appropriate.  

Monitoring or recording of your calls, emails, text messages and other communications may take place in accordance with UK law, and in particular for: business purposes, such as for quality control and training; processing necessary for the entering into or the performance of a contract; to prevent unauthorised use of our telecommunication systems and web sites; to ensure effective systems operation; to meet any legal obligation; in your vital interests; in order to prevent or detect crime; and for the purposes of the legitimate interests of the data controller. Please visit the following web sites for further information:

---|---|---  
  | 

**ii)**

| 

**Non-personal**

If you wish to visit our web site, you can do so without disclosing any personal information, although we may use cookies and collect non-personal information about your browsing (click-stream) activities.

‘Cookies’ are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. You can find out more about the way cookies work on [http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/). 

We use cookies for a number of purposes, for instance to enable us to simplify the logging on process for registered users, to help ensure the security and authenticity of registered users, to provide the mechanisms for online quotes and to enable traffic monitoring.

Non-registered visitors of the site are sent anonymous cookies to keep track of their browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile.

Whilst you do not need to allow your browser to accept personal cookies in order to browse our web site or access many of our services, you must have session cookies enabled if you wish to quote online or access any areas reserved for registered users. Session cookies do not hold personal information, they merely enable you to progress safely through our secure web site.

Without session cookies, we are unable to provide you with a quote or access our web site. If you have any queries regarding session cookies and our use of them, please feel free to contact the Information Security Officer on 029 20434252.

You can block all personal cookies and still obtain a quote but the web site won't function if session state cookies are disabled.

Most Internet browsers allow you to turn off the cookie function. If you want to know how to do this please look at the help menu on your browser. As described above this will restrict the services you can use.

If you use our web site, then please be aware that it will contain links to other web sites. We accept no responsibility or liability for the content of these web sites. If you choose to visit another web site via our web site, you will need to contact them separately to have your name and address deleted from any list they might hold.  

  | 

We will endeavour to treat all your personal information as private and confidential. Other than under the terms of this Privacy Statement we will not disclose any of your information to anyone. We would like to bring your attention though to our obligations to disclose information in the following four exceptional cases permitted by law. These are:

  * where we are legally compelled to do so; 
  * where there is a duty to the public to disclose; 
  * where disclosure is required to protect our interest; 
  * where disclosure is made at your request or with your consent. 

---|---  
  
  | 

From time to time we will employ agents and subcontractors to process your information on our behalf. We may allow such agents and subcontractors, including collection agencies and field collectors, access to your personal information. The same duty of confidentiality and security will apply to our agents and subcontractors and all processing will be carried out under our instruction.

Should you take the decision to make a complaint about the service we have provided, we may be obliged to forward details about your complaint, including your personal information, to the relevant ombudsman in existence at the time. You can be assured that they are similarly obliged to adhere to the Data Protection Act and keep your information strictly confidential.

In the unfortunate event that you have to make a claim then we will need to disclose information with any other parties involved in that claim. This may include third parties involved with the claim, any third party's insurer, their solicitor or similar representative, medical teams, police and other investigators. If necessary we may also have to investigate your claims and conviction history in the course of administering the claim. You can be assured that we will keep such investigations strictly confidential.

Insurers pass information to the Claims Underwriting and Exchange Register, run by Insurance Database Services (IDS) and the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register, run by the Association of British Insurers (ABI). The aim is to help insurers check information provided and also prevent fraudulent claims. When we deal with your request for insurance, if applicable, we may search these registers. Under the conditions of your policy, you must tell us about any incident (such as accident or theft) which may or may not give rise to a claim. When you tell us about an incident we will pass information, relating to it, to the registers.

Your policy details will be added to the Motor Insurance Database (MID), run by the Motor Insurers' Information Centre (MIIC). MID data may be used by the DVLA and the DVLNI for the purpose of Electronic Vehicle Licensing and by the Police for the purposes of establishing whether a driver's use of the vehicle is likely to be covered by a motor insurance policy and/or for preventing and detecting crime. If you are involved in an accident (in the UK or abroad), other UK insurers, the Motor Insurers' Bureau and MIIC may search the MID to obtain relevant policy information.

Persons pursuing a claim in respect of a road traffic accident (including citizens of other countries) may also obtain relevant information which is held on the MID.

You can find out more about this from us, or at [www.miic.org.uk](http://www.miic.org.uk/).

We make searches about you at credit reference agencies who will supply us with information, including information from the Electoral Register and credit information. The agencies will record details of the search whether or not this application proceeds. The searches will not be seen or used by lenders to assess your ability to obtain credit. We may use scoring methods to assess this application and to verify your identity. Credit searches and other information which is provided to us and/or the credit reference agencies, about you and those with whom you are linked financially may be used by Admiral Insurance Services Limited and other companies if you, or other members of your household, apply for other facilities including insurance applications and claims. This information may also be used for debt tracing and the prevention of money laundering as well as the management of your account. Alternatively, we may ask you to provide physical forms of identification.  

**Fraud prevention and detection notice**

In order to prevent and detect fraud we may at any time:

  * share information about you with our other Group companies; 
  * pass your details to Insurance Hunter a central insurance application and claims checking system whereby it may be checked against information held by Insurance Hunter and shared with other insurers; 
  * check your details with fraud prevention agencies and if you give us false or inaccurate information and we suspect fraud, we will record this. 

We and other organisations may also use and search these records to:

  * help make decisions about credit and credit related services for you and members of your household; 
  * help make decisions on motor, household, business, credit, life and other insurance proposals and insurance claims for you and members of your household; 
  * trace debtors, recover debt, prevent fraud and to manage your accounts or insurance policies; 
  * check your identity to prevent money laundering unless you furnish us with other satisfactory proof of identity; 
  * undertake credit searches and additional fraud searches. If you would like details of the agencies we use please call 0800 052 3144. 

---|---  
  
  | 

We recognise that our customers are increasingly concerned about how companies protect personal information from misuse and abuse and about privacy in general. We are constantly reviewing and enhancing our technical, physical and managerial procedures and rules to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, accidental loss and/or destruction.

On our web sites we have taken care to protect any information that you have given us by providing you with a User ID and a password. We also use industry standard secure sockets layer (SSL) 128 bit encryption technology, for example, to encrypt sensitive information such as your credit card and other financial information.

The User ID and unique password relevant to some of our web site users, helps us to protect your personal information. You must keep this password safe and must not disclose it to anyone. You may need a User ID and password to access your personal information on our web site. We will accept no responsibility or liability if a third party obtains and uses your User ID and password. You must tell us immediately if you have lost your User ID or password, or if you believe a third party may have obtained it. Please also tell us if you would like us to change your User ID or password for any reason.

When you ask for a quote from us, we will process the data on a secure server. Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator will confirm that you are in a secure area by displaying an unbroken key or a lock in the bottom right corner of your browser window.

Some organisations have a security feature called a firewall to protect their computer systems. These firewalls may prevent you from connecting to our secure server to get a quote. If you are at work and cannot connect to our site, please consult with your IT administrator to learn more. 

Please be aware that communications over the Internet, such as emails/webmails, are not secure unless they have been encrypted.

Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered - this is the nature of the World Wide Web/Internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

It may be necessary to transfer your personal information to other Group companies or service providers located in countries outside of the EEA**. This may happen where our servers or suppliers and service providers are based outside of the EEA or where you use our services and products while visiting countries outside of the EEA. The data protection and other laws of these countries may not be as comprehensive as those in the UK or the EU - in these instances we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights are respected.

** The European Economic Area (EEA) currently comprises the Member states of the European Union plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein  
  
---|---  

### 6\.    ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION

  | 

You can write to us at any time to obtain details of the personal information we may hold about you. *Please write to the Data Protection Officer, Admiral Insurance Services Limited, Floor 22, Capital Tower, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AZ..

Please quote your name and address together with your policy number. We would be grateful if could also provide brief details of what information you want a copy of (this helps us to more readily locate your data).

We will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any personal information we may hold about you. To this extent therefore, we would be grateful if you could provide two forms of identification such as a copy of a driving licence, passport or document containing your signature and a copy of a recent utility bill that confirms your address.

*in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 we are entitled to charge £10 to cover the administration costs involved with this process. Please make accompanying cheques payable to 'Admiral Insurance Services Limited'.  
  
---|---  
  
  | 

We reserve the right to amend or modify this Privacy Policy Statement at any time and in response to changes in applicable data protection and privacy legislation.

The Data Controller is Admiral Insurance Services Limited (Registered number: 02686904). Admiral, Bell, Diamond, elephant.co.uk and Admiral Business are trading names of Admiral Insurance Services Limited. At all times Admiral Insurance Services Limited will remain the ultimate data controller. In this Privacy Statement 'we', 'us', and 'our' means Admiral Insurance Services Limited.

If you have any enquiry about our data protection and privacy policy or practices, please write to the Data Protection Officer, Admiral Insurance Services Limited, Floor 22, Capital Tower, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AZ.  
  
---|---  
  
Version 07/05
